8051 Meade St, Westminster, CO 80031

□ (+1) 303-903-5681 | **S** tylerjw@gmail.com | **O** tylerjw | **S** tylerweaver

# **Summary**\_

Highly motivated software engineer with experience leading long-term software projects involving optimizing algorithms for wireless communication. Embedded electronics hobbyist who enjoys using software and hardware to automate and solve problems. Interested in working on a team creating meaningful products.

### Skills\_

**Programming** C/C++, Python, Matlab, JavaScript, Perl, Groovy, Processing, Java

**Tools** GCC, GDB, Make, Valgrind, SublimeText, Git, SVN, GPG, Bash

**Embedded** Arduino, RPi, Mbed, ARM, SPI, I2C, GPS, CV, IMU

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

**LGS Innovations** Westminster, CO

SOFTWARE ENGINEER III Jun. 2014 - PRESENT

- Optimized C++ polyphase resampler and fir filter to run on ARM with NEON instructions
  - Filter design using same method as fir2 using fftw
  - Generic resampling implementation for arbitrary upsample and downsample rates
  - Used compiler optimizer output and knowledge of architecture to structure data and loop to take advantage of vectorization
  - Resulting fir filter and resampler used less instructions than intel IPP implementation and ran only 8x slower on A53 than on an i7 using intel optimized vector routines
  - Optimizing for vectorization resulted in 10x speed up over simple for loops
- Interface library for new SDR using protobuf messaging and VRT over Ethernet
  - Protobuf messaging with thread for asynchronous status updating
  - VRT over UDP for receiving sample data over a 10Ge link
- Adversarial Research on 802.11b Physical Layer using an SDR
  - Prototype C++ code using USRP to test RTS/CTS ranging technique
  - Developed unique method to improve ranging measurements based on observed behavior of AP messaging
  - Debugging using Wireshark to observe call and response
- · Created library for detecing oddly configured cellular basestations
- P25 scanner library
  - Prototyped in python, Implemented in C++
  - FFT narrow band energy window detect for fast scanning
  - FSW search used for timing and frequency offset correction
  - Viterbi, Reed-Solomon, BCH, and CRC Decoding
  - Framing and Message Parsing for all Broadcast messages
- Radio interface libraries for scanner application
  - Epig Sidekig with Placekig GPS
  - Ettus USRP N210 and B210 with support for hotplugging
- MPT1327 scanner library

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

- Prototyped in matlab, Implemented in C++
- Goertzel based fast reject for fast scanning
- IPP Parallelized FM demodulator
- Feedback timing recovery algorithm for MSK
- CRC checker and Bit/Message parsing
- Ported matlab library for unknown signal analysis into C++
  - Arbitrary PSK and FSK input signal characterization
  - Implemented algorithms in C++ based off matlab code written by PhD

**TecStar Consulting** Broomfield, CO Mar. 2014 - Jun. 2014

· Selenium automation testing of websites with Python and Java

· Android app development for Rachio sprinkler controller

#### **Colorado Army National Guard**

5/19th SFGA

Oct. 2008 - Oct. 2016

SATELLITE COMMUNICATIONS SYSTEMS OPERATOR/MAINTAINER (25S)

- Deployed in support of Special Operations Task Force East in Afghanistan (2013)
- · Developed software to automate extracting and converting geo locations from Google Earth files

Tyler J. Weaver · Résumé JANUARY 22, 2019

## **Education**

**DeVry University** Westminster, CO

**B.S. IN COMPUTER ENGINEERING TECHNOLOGY** Aug. 2010 - Mar. 2014

- 3.96 GPA
- · Weather balloon payload navigation project
- Tutor for engineering program students

# **Extracurricular Activity**

**Embedded Electronics** Lakewood, CO

RALLY BUILD ENDURANCE RACE TEAM

Dec. 2018

- Microcontroller CAN bus communication
- Power control circuits for motor control and high side switching
- Sensor signal conditioning circuits
- · Current measuring using Opamp

**Automation for Airbnb using Smartthings controller** Englewood, CO

FORK OF OPEN SOURCE DOOR LOCK SMART APP

Aug. 2017

- iCal parser and event logic for setting lock codes for each guest based on phone number
- Push notifications to phone app when guest uses their code for the first time

Co-driver computer for race car Englewood, CO

WEAVERING RALLY TEAM

- Jul. 2017 · Embedded system for assisting co-driver during competition
- GPS tracking and timing on Arduino microcontroller with 7-segment display
- · Competed in Rally Colorado 2017

Software for identifying ideal rental properties Englewood, CO

Mar. 2017 - Jun. 2017

- **AUTOMATED INVESTMENT ADVISOR**
- Scrapy scrapers for Realtor to find new listings
- · Automated AWS EC2 Proxy instances for defeating Realtor.com tracking of bots
- · MongoDb database for storing listings for analysis
- Airbnb scraper for finding similar properties listed for short term rental
- Daily PDF report generated using latex
- Developed locally and then deployed onto AWS
- · Attempted to sell reports to Realtors

**Colorado Robot Challenge** Golden, CO

COMPUTER VISION ON EMBEDDED HARDWARE

Oct. 2013 - Mar. 2014

Oct. 2017

- Real-time firmware for 3d stereo vision sensor on XMOS and Nvidia hardware
- Custom BCB prototyping with surface mount components

splintermail.com Westminster, CO

INSTALL SCRIPTS AND TESTING

- MacOS install script
- · Beta testing

Tyler J. Weaver · Résumé JANUARY 22, 2019